Saralee Hamilton Papers
Sophia Smith Collection
- SERIES IV. RESOURCES
  - "Poverty in the American Dream: Women and Children First" by Karin Stallard, Barbara Ehrenreich, and Holly Sklar, Institute for New Communications pamphlet no. 1, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Pro-Choice Public Education Project information packetcirca 2004 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - "Reproductive Justice Briefing Book: A Primer on Reproductive Justice and Social Change," undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - "Resources on female genital mutilation: Bibliography, Audiovisuals & Organisations/Campaigns," Women Living Under Muslim Laws Research, Information & Documentation UnitDec 1994 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - "Sex Roles and Female Oppression: a collection of articles by Dana Densmore," New England Free Pressundated (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - "Sexual and Reproductive Rights Briefing Cards," (English and Spanish), Family Care International 2000 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Sindiato Nacional del la Industria de la Costura, Confeccion, el Vestido, similares y conexos "19 de Septiembre publications: "Las Costureras nos organizamos," "La Industria del vestido," and "Los Estatutuos de nuestro sindicato," undated (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - "Valiant Migrant Women (Los Mujeres Valerosas)" by Joy Hintz 1982 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - "With Babies and Banners" Study/Activity Booklet by Phyllis Palmer and Joan Skolnick, Hidden From History Program 1982 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - "Woman Vote: A Citizen Action Kit for People of Faith," Religious Network for the Equality of Women 1984 update (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - "Women…a world survey" by Ruth Leger Sivard, World Priorities 1985 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Women at Work: A Photographic Documentary by Betty Medsger 1975 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - "Women in the Texas Workforce: Yesterday and Today," People's History in Texas, Inc. 1979 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - "Women Organizers: A Beginning Collection of References and Resources," The Women Organizers' CollectiveNov 1989 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - "Women: The Longest Revolution" by Juliet Mitchell, New England Free Press, reprint of a 1966 article, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - "Women's Economic Agenda Project: A Call to Action by and for California Women1987 (Box 11, Folder 4)
- SERIES V. SUBJECT FILES
  - Abortion
    - Generalcirca 1970-91 (Box 11, Folder 5-9)
    - Human Life Amendment and bills 1974-82, undated (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Medicaid funding 1979-80 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Roe v. Casey 1979 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Roe v. Wade 1985 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Rosie Jimenez Fund 1983, undated (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Rust v. Sullivan 1991 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Anti-imperialismundated (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Contraceptives
    - General 1979-84, undated (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Depo-provera
      - General 1978-86, undated (Box 11, Folder 18-19)
      - "Depo-Provera: An Anthropological Analysis" by Andrew James Russell, M.S. theseis, University of Pennsylvania 1984 (Box 12, Folder 1)
      - "The Depo-Provera Weapon" by Gena Corea 1979 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Disability 1982, undated (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Equal Rights Amendment 1980, undated (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Household workers 1984-86, undated (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Infant formula 1981 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Labor/workers' rights 1981, 1995, undated (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Lesbians 1970, 1983-85, undated (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous 1978-97, undated (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Native American women 1975-2005, undated (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Nonviolence 1983-2005 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Political prisoners 1985-87 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Population 1974-94, undated (Box 12, Folder 13-14)
  - Pro-family movementcirca 1981 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Rape and sexual abuse 1976-92, undated (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Reproductive Rights
    - General 1977-2004, undated (Box 12, Folder 17-19)
    - Health issues, Africa 1997-2004, undated (Box 12, Folder 20-21)
    - Pennsylvania 1977-83, undated (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Religion 1979-83 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Reproductive technologies 1985-89 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Right wing 1980, undated (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Status of women 1970-99, undated (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Sterilization, 1968-80
    - General 1968-85, undated (Box 13, Folder 6-8)
    - Native American women 1976-81, undated (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Teen age sexuality 1996, undated (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Trafficking 1986, undated (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Violence 1983, 2005, undated (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Women
    - General 1975-2005 (Box 13, Folder 13-14)
    - Africa 1976-2004, undated (Box 13, Folder 15-16)
    - Asia 1980-96, undated (Box 13, Folder 17-18)
    - Caribbean 1994, undated (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Central America 1984, undated (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - China/Hong Kongundated (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Guatemala 1983-87 (Box 14, Folder 3-4)
    - Iraq 1980 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Japan 1986 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Korea 1980, 1995, undated (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Nicaragua 1983, 1985 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Philippines 1980-93, undated (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Serbiaundated (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Tibet 1995 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Zimbabwe 1981 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Women and development 1988-2002, undated (Box 14, Folder 13-14)
  - Women and Quakerism 1955, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Women and peace 1911, 1982, undated (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Women and race 1998-2001, undated (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Women and war 1972-2002, undated (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Women and work
    - General 1981-91, undated (Box 15, Folder 1-2)
    - Germany 1985, undated (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Women's health 1997-98, undated (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Women's human rights 1975-2004, undated (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Women's Liberation 1969-82, undated (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Women's movement in Philadelphia 1981-87 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Workplace health and rights 1980-90, undated (Box 15, Folder 8)
- SERIES VI. AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS
  - Slide presentations
    - "Grassroots Feminism in Mexico" slideshow with notes for presentationundated (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - "Sterilization Abuse," Boston Committee to End Sterilization Abuse: slideshow with several versions of script in English and Spanish,undated (Box 15, Folder 2-3)
    - "Who's In Control? Microtechnology and Women's Work," Participatory Research Group, Toronto, Ontario: slideshow with audiotaped narration on cassetteundated, [see also Audiotapes below] (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - "Women in Korea," Committee for a New Korea Policy: slideshow with script and audio narrationundated, [see also Audiotapes below] (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Audiotapes
    - "Charlotte's tapes" [probably Charlotte Bunch] NGO Forum, Nairobi, "What is Feminism Panel 1985 [2 audiocassettes] (Box 16, Folder 1-2)
    - "The Gates of Greenham: A Peace Passion for Today for Chorus and Orchestra" by Tony Biggin, Sain Records 1986 [2 cassettes] (Box 16, Folder 3-4)
    - Women 2000: A Symposium on Future Directions for Human Rights, Center for Women's Global Leadership, HMR Duplications, 2000 [4 cassettes] (Box 16, Folder 5-8)
    - Making Contact: "Women's Rights, Human Rights," a UN Women's Desk Program26 July 2000, National Radio Project [1 cassette] (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - "Who's In Control? Microtechnology and Women's Work," Participatory Research Group, Toronto, Ontario: audiotaped narrationundated [1 cassette] (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - "Women in Korea," Committee for a New Korea Policy: audiotaped narrationundated [1 cassette] (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Videotapes
    - Women's Gathering, American Friends Service Committee women, Rock Cleft Retreat Center, ColoradoJun 1973, [helical scan video-digital file available] (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - "Breaking the Chains that Oppress Us," slides to video transferJul 1986 (Philippines), produced by GABRIELA National Women's Coalition [VHS] (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - "Seeds of Promise…The Critical Roles of Women in Food Production, OEF International 1987 [VHS] (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Leaning Economics: Empowering Women for Action, Religious Network for Equality for Women (RNEW) 1988 [VHS] (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - "Centering On Peace: Maquiladoras," Bullfrog Films, Inc. 1989 [VHS] (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - A Conference in Defense of Roe, ACLU Reproductive Freedom Project5 Oct 1989 [VHS] (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - "A Woman Named Mary: The Feminization of Poverty," United Church of Christ, Augsburg Publishing House, undated (1990s) [VHS] (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - "Four Walls…No Borders: Mexican Women and the Struggle for Survival" film by Rachael Kamel 1990 (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - "Arab Women at Work," a film by Lynne Osborne and Maureen Ali, United Nations Development Programme 1990 [VHS] (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - "In Her Own Image," a project of Media Network promoting the use of social change media 1991 [VHS] (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - "What's the Cost of Your Blouse?" A project of the Northern California Council on Interfaith Justice and Work, Oakland, CA, Open Window Images 1992 [VHS] 18 min. (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - "The F-Word," a videotape by Marcia Jarmel and Erin Gallagher 1994, Women Make Movies [VHS] (Box 16, Folder 23)
    - "Are We the Enemy" Khmer Women's Voices & Women's Media Center (land mines) 1995: 12 min [VHS] (Box 16, Folder 24)
    - "Legal But Out of Reach: Six Women's Abortion Stories," National Network of Abortion Funds 2000 [VHS with printed discussion guide] (Box 16, Folder 25)
    - "WTO: In Whose Hands?" A video by the Women's Division, General Board of Global Ministries, United Methodist Church 2000 [VHS] (Box 16, Folder 26)
    - "Living History: Women from Civil Rights to Black Power," the Stanford Channel, Stanford University 2001 [VHS] (Box 16, Folder 27)
    - "On Sistahs" (tape of local TV show-Philadelphia WYBE) Women of Color, undated [VHS] (Box 16, Folder 28)
    - Uncle Sam Film Project for Nationwide Women's Program, AFSC: film outtake clips and "Best of Ninotchka," undated [VHS], [digital file available] (Box 16, Folder 29)
    - 5 minute videos, women, undated [VHS, NTSC format] (Box 16, Folder 30)
  - Compact disks-DVDs
    - "Gender & Humanitarian Assistance Resource Kit," Inter-Agency Standing Committee sub-Working Group on Gender and Humanitarian ResponseFeb 2001 [CD-R] (Box 16, Folder 31)
    - "From the Inside of Our Skins," a video report on the World Court of Women Against Racism, Disc #2 [CD-R] 2001?, [digital file available] (Box 16, Folder 32)
    - "Feeling, Contemplating, and Building the Future IV," Continental Meeting of Indigenous Women of the Americas, CHIRAPAQ, Centro de Culturas Indigenas del Peru, Lima, Peru4-7 Apr 2004 [DVD], [digital file available] (Box 16, Folder 33)
    - "Gender and Justice in the Gene Age: a feminist meeting on new reproductive and genetic technologies," Meeting Report, New York City6-7 May 2004 [CD], [digital file available] (Box 16, Folder 34)
    - "The Runway Peace Project Kit: featuring the video documentary "Fashion Resistance to Militarism," Women of Color Resource Center 2006 [2 DVD], [digital file available] (Box 16, Folder 35-36)
    - "Women's Learning Partnership for Rights, Development, and Peace" [CD-cracked and unreadable] (Box 16, Folder 37)
    - "Gender Audit Facilitators Guide: Promoting Gender Equity," Commission on the Advancement of Women, InterAction, undated [CD-ROM], unopened (Box 16, Folder 38)
- OVERSIZE MATERIALS AND ARTIFACTS
  - 8 political buttons (Box 17)
  - Oversize materials from Series II, III, and V (Box 17)